# Sam Kritchevsky

GitHub | LinkedIn | sam.kritch@gmail.com | 336-414-8694

## **ABOUT ME**

I'm a software engineer with 5 years' experience.. My professional experience is primarily as what might be called a "data generalist". I contributed to a modern data stack in many capacities: backend SWE, DE, ML, DS, and analytics. I primarily use Python, Scala, and SQL, and have a strong math background. I'm currently returning to work after a personal sabbatical, looking for a position where I can be productive quickly and where my work can have strategic impact. I'm also interested in roles in adjacent or specialized areas like full-stack engineering and ML.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages : Python, Scala, SQL, Typescript

**Technologies** : PostgreSQL, Redshift, Elasticsearch, Redis, PostGIS, Spark, Flink, RabbitMQ, DBT, Docker, Luigi, Dag-

ster, React, various AWS (EMR, Lambda, Kinesis, S3, Neptune).

**Roles** : Data Engineering, Data Science, Data Platform, Backend Engineering, Analytics, ML Engineering

#### **EXPERIENCE**

2016-2021 Seatgeek 1.5 Years

Sr. Software Engineer, Data Platform Tech Lead

Tech lead of team of six engineers. Projects included:

 Rewrite of our in-house event ingestion service in Flink + Kafka, adding features and massivley improving scaleability. I advocated for the project, designed the system, and implemented most of the business logic. Functionality included:

- \* Fanouts to front page recommendations, push notifications, Redshift, and a planned online feature store.
- \* Realtime sessionization, supporting late-arriving data.
- Validation against a repository of JSONSchemas with realtime alerting
- Rollout of a standardized Jupyter setup based on Docker, Papermill, and NBViewer.
- Deployment of Amundsen, an OSS data-discovery platform, with a custom AWS Neptune backend.
- Owned and maintained the core data stack of Druzhba, DBT, Looker, Luigi, Redshift, and other AWS products.

Sr. Data Scientist, Data Scientist II

2.5 Years

Location: New York, NY

Data Scientist II

Specialized in user recommendation signals and our event catalog, working in Spark, SQL, and Python. Projects included:

- Algorithms for the weekly newsletter, cart abandonment and price drops notifications, in Spark + SQL. (This work tripled the revenue associated with the weekly newsletter.)
- Event and performer popularity models for event recommendations and search, built with Keras
- Entity-linking algorithm deduplicating users and device for marketing attribution and funnel KPIs.
- Ongoing involvement in design and measurement of metrics for recommendations, search, and CRM marketing.

Software Engineer, Discovery

1 Year

Contributed features for search, CRM marketing, and frontpage recommendations.

## **Other Experience**

Greater Harlem Coalition (volunteer)

2022

Contributed data analysis, writing, editing, and website administration for a community advocacy group. My data pipeline uses DBT, Python, Dagster, and PostGIS (code here.)

Physics Recitation Teacher 2014-2016

# **EDUCATION**

**University of Wisconsin** 

Madison, WI 2013-2015

Coursework towards Physics Ph.D.

**University of North Carolina** 

Chapel Hill, NC

B.S. Physics

2012